Guide to the Thomas Whiteside papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Thomas Whiteside Papers,
1839-1995
[Bulk Dates: 1952-1992]
Whiteside, Thomas, 1918-1997.
29 linear ft. (23 record containers, 1 document box, 4 flat boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1545
7971726
Thomas Whiteside was an American journalist, born in 1918. He died in 1997. Whiteside wrote for The New Yorker for over 45 years. He covered such topics in his articles and books as cable television, the cigarette industry, the channel tunnel, chemical weapons (notably 2, 4, 5-T, a component of Agent Orange), Ralph Nader, Stig Wennerstrom, and yellow rain. It has been said that Whiteside's work on Agent Orange led directly to the congressional hearings which discussed the dangers of the substance. By the end of the hearings, the Surgeon General of the United States had announced restrictions on the use of the herbicide. The collection contains material related to the articles that Whiteside contributed to The New Yorker. The files include audiocassettes, book reviews, correspondence, drafts, galleys, notebooks and notes, research files, and typescripts. There is a small section of the collection that contains personal papers not tied directly to specific articles or books. The material ranges in date from the 1950s to the 1990s, spanning the time Whiteside worked at The New Yorker.
Biographical Note
Thomas Whiteside was born in Berwick-Upon-Tweed, England in 1918. He moved to the US by way of Canada in 1940 to study at the University of Chicago. During WWII, Whiteside worked for the Office of War Propaganda, compiling reports on Axis propaganda. In 1945, he became a US citizen and joined the staff of Newsweek as a foreign affairs writer. Whiteside later went on to write for The New Republic and joined the staff of The New Yorker in 1950.
As a journalist, Whiteside wrote for The New Yorker for over 45 years. He covered a range of topics for the magazine's various series - Annals of Advertising, Annals of Business, Annals of Crime, Annals of the Cold War, Annals of Espionage, Annals of Migration, Annals of Television, Onward and Upward with the Arts, Reporter at Large, and Talk of the Town. The topics Whiteside wrote on were broad and complex, including pieces on cable television, the Channel Tunnel, cigarettes and the cigarette industry, computer crime, dioxins (most notably 2, 4, 5-T, a component in Agent Orange), the publishing industry, Stig Wennerstrom, and yellow rain. Whiteside also wrote several biographical articles for the magazine's "Profiles" section. This included pieces on Teddy Adams, Captain Kurt Carlsen, Daniel Fraad Jr., Ralph Nader, Rosser Reeves, David Susskind, and Sylvester "Pat" Weaver. Several of Whiteside's articles, most of which were published in serial form formed the basis for longer book length works. He published 11 books, working with a number of different publishing houses and literary agencies.
Whiteside was married to Marie Whiteside and had three children. He lived his later years in West Cornwall, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the papers of Thomas Whiteside and in the main, relates to Whiteside's professional career as a journalist, as represented in Series I: Writings. There is a small second series of personal papers and material not tied directly to an article or book. The collection primarily pertains to the articles Whiteside wrote for The New Yorker. These files range in date from 1952-1992, covering the time Whiteside wrote for the magazine. The files include research articles and clippings, audiocassettes, correspondence, drafts, galleys and proofs, notebooks, both handwritten and typed notes, and typescripts.
Arrangement
Material is arranged into two series:
Series I: Writings, 1839-1995
Subseries I.1: Published Articles and Books, 1839-1991
Subseries I.2: Unpublished Articles, 1962-1995
Subseries I.3: General Research Files, 1961-1987
Series II: Personal Papers, 1940-1995
Subjects
New Yorker--(New York, N.Y.: 1925); Carlsen, Kurt; Nader, Ralph; Reeves, Rosser; Susskind, David, 1920-1987.; Weaver, Pat, 1908-2002.; Wennerström, Stig; Whiteside, Thomas, 1918-1997.; Seveso (Italy); Advertising Cigarettes; Agent Orange; Cable television; Channel Tunnel (Coquelles, France, and Folkestone, England); Chemical warfare; Cigarettes; Computer crimes; Defoliants--War use; Defoliation--Vietnam; Dioxins; Herbicides; Joe Camel (Advertising character); Journalism; Journalism--United States; Publishers and publishing; Audiocassettes; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Drafts (documents); Galley proofs; Notebooks; Notes; Typescripts
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least 2 business days in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Karen Falcon, Anne Whiteside, and James Huddleston Whiteside Gift 2010-2011 2010.2011.M020
The Thomas Whiteside Papers were the gift of Karen Falcon, Anne Whiteside, and James Huddleston Whiteside to the Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Columbia University in 2010.
Finding aid online and in repository folder level control
Online finding aid available.
- Series I: Writings, 1839-1991
  Series I: Writings consists of the material related to articles and books published by Thomas Whiteside as well as research files for unpublished works and general research files, or those untied to a specific book or article. A majority of the material pertains to articles Whiteside wrote for The New Yorker. Themes get repeated over the course of this series. For instance, writing on dioxins are represented in article and book form. This is the case with the article, "The Pendulum and the Toxic Cloud" that was later published as a book under the same name. In other cases, books about certain topics later show up in the magazine. For instance, his series on Ralph Nader, "Countervailing Force" was first published in book form as The Investigation of Ralph Nader: General Motors vs. One Determined Man.
  - Subseries I.1: Published Articles and Books, 1839-1995
    Subseries I.1: Published Articles and Books contains material related to articles and books published by Thomas Whiteside. In general the articles were written for The New Yorker. There are a few outliers, for instance, Whiteside's piece about the 1968 Democratic National Convention, "Corridor of Mirrors" was published in the Columbia Journalism Review. Whiteside contributed to The New Yorker for over 45 years, a majority of the articles he wrote for the magazine are represented in this subseries. He wrote 11 books, and those too are represented, if however briefly, in this subseries. The files consist of research files, made up of articles, audiocassettes, clippings, notebooks, and typed notes. Also present around each article are related correspondence, drafts, galleys and proofs, and typescripts. The correspondence is, for the most part, letters that Whiteside received in congratulations of publication of his book or article. A few contributors of note include, Andy Rooney and John Kenneth Galbraith. There is also correspondence with Whiteside and his publishers and literary agents, Yale University Press, Wesleyan University Press, among others. Some letters to and from Allen Dulles pertaining to a book blurb for Wennerstrom can be found in the correspondence file for "An Agent in Place."
    - 2, 4, 5-T/Dioxins/The Pendulum and the Toxic Cloud
      - "2, 4, 5-T"--Typescript, 1975-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1982, undated, (7 folders) (Box 1)
      - "Decision on 2, 4, 5-T"--Galley, undated (Box 28)
      - The Pendulum and the Toxic Cloud (book)
        - Appendix--Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1)
        - Book Reviews, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
        - Book Reviews and Publicity, 1979, undated (Box 1)
        - Contract Rider, undated (Box 1)
        - Correspondence
          - 1979-1983, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
          - Science Review, 1979 (Box 1)
          - Snyder, Mary (American Legion Post 557 Herbicide Incident), 1979-1980 (Box 1)
          - Yale University Press, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
        - Publicity Materials, 1978-1979, undated (Box 1)
        - Sedwick and Jackson Publishers, 1978 (Box 1)
        - Typescript (partial), undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
        - Yale University Press, 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 1)
      - "The Pendulum and 2, 4, 5-T"
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1976-1977, (5 folders) (Box 1)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1977 (Box 22)
      - "The Pendulum and the Toxic Cloud"
        - Draft, undated (Box 1)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 1)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1977 (Box 23)
      - Research Files
        - 1961-1981, undated, (6 folders) (Box 1)
        - 1972-1981, undated, (8 folders) (Box 2)
        - Agent Orange, Disposal of, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
        - Clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
        - Defoliation, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2)
        - Dioxin Planning Conference, 1974 (Box 2)
        - Dow Chemical, 1975 (Box 2)
        - Forest Uses, 1975 (Box 2)
        - Givaudan Paper, 1976 (Box 2)
        - Haig, Alexander M., 1981 (Box 2)
        - Notebooks, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
        - Notes
          - 1977-1978, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2)
          - Environmental Protection Agency, 1975, undated (Box 2)
        - PCB, undated (Box 2)
        - Rachel Carson Trust for the Living Environment, Inc., 1975 (Box 2)
        - Seveso, Italy, 1976-1979, (2 folders) (Box 2)
        - Spontaneous Abortions, 1976, undated (Box 2)
        - TCDD Scientific Conference (Milan, Italy), 1976 (Box 2)
    - An Agent in Place/Stig Wennerstrom
      - An Agent in Place: the Wennerstrom Affair (book)
        - Agreement with Ballantine Books, 1981 (Box 2)
        - Book Reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
        - Correspondence
          - 1968, undated (Box 2)
          - The Viking Press, 1966 (Box 2)
        - Publicity, undated (Box 2)
      - "An Agent in Place"
        - Galley Inserts, undated (Box 2)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1965 (Box 2)
      - "An Eagle in Place"-- Typescript, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1966, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Research Files
        - Notebooks, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
        - Notes, 1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
        - Wennerstrom Case--Reports and Transcripts, circa 1960s (Box 19)
        - Wennerstrom Case--Reports and Transcripts, circa 1960s (Box 20)
        - Notes, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - "Anything Adverse"
      - Correspondence
        - 1975, 1979 (Box 3)
        - Friendly, Fred to Shawn, William (copy), 1975 (Box 3)
      - Notebooks, 1974 (Box 3)
    - "Better and Better"
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1952-1953 (Box 21)
      - Research Files
        - Clipping Sample (copies), 1923, 1926 (Box 3)
        - Notebooks, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
        - Notes, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - The Big Puff--Book Reviews, 1955 (Box 3)
    - The Blockbuster Complex (book and article)
      - The Blockbuster Complex (book)
        - Agreements and Licensing, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
        - Book Reviews, 1981-1983, (5 folders) (Box 3)
        - Correspondence
          - 1979-1986, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
          - Columbia University Press, 1981 (Box 3)
          - Indiana University Press, 1980 (Box 3)
          - Wesleyan University Press, 1981-1985, (2 folders) (Box 3)
        - Royalty Report, 1985, 1988 (Box 3)
        - Typescript, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
      - "The Blockbuster Complex"
        - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3)
        - Typescript
          - 1980, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
          - Addition to Part II, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 3)
          - Draft, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Research Files
        - Articles, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
        - Authors, undated (Box 4)
        - Geis, Bernard, 1975-1978, undated (Box 4)
        - Notebooks, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4)
        - Notes
          - 1977-1978, undated, (6 folders) (Box 4)
          - Krantz, Judith, 1977-1980, undated (Box 4)
          - Part II, 1979-1980, undated (Box 4)
          - Straus, Roger, 1977-1980, undated (Box 4)
    - "Cable"
      - Correspondence
        - 1982-1985, 1996 (Box 4)
        - Stein, Howard, 1969, 1979, undated (Box 4)
      - Galleys/Typescript Part I, 1984 (Box 4)
      - Galleys/Typescript Part II, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      - Galleys/Typescript Part III, 1984 (Box 4)
      - Part I--Deleted Material, undated (Box 4)
      - Part III--Draft, undated (Box 4)
      - Research Files
        - AT&T, 1982 (Box 4)
        - CBS, 1982 (Box 4)
        - Cities, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 4)
        - Clippings, 1981-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
        - Concluding Section, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
        - Franchising
          - Milwaukee, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 4)
          - New York, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
        - HBO, 1978-1985, undated, (4 folders) (Box 5)
        - Lobbying, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
        - Notebooks, 1982 (Box 5)
        - Notes, 1981-1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 5)
        - PBS, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
        - Petrie, Donald, undated (Box 5)
        - Politics, 1982-1984 (Box 5)
        - Privacy, 1982, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 5)
        - Public Television, 1981-1982, undated (Box 5)
        - Sources, 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
        - Taylor, Arthur, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
        - Warner AMEX, 1982-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5)
        - Warner Communications, 1974-1982 (Box 5)
        - Weaver, Sylvester, 1964-1982, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Typescript
        - undated, (5 folders) (Box 5)
        - French Section, undated (Box 5)
    - "C.E.O. TV"
      - Correspondence, 1987, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
      - Galleys, 1987 (Box 5)
      - Research Files, 1982-1986 (Box 5)
    - Channel Tunnel
      - "The Channel Tunnel"--Draft, undated (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1991, undated (Box 5)
      - Research Files
        - 1907-1986, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5)
        - 1839, 1866-1905, 1930-1936, 1960, (3 folders) (Box 21)
        - Clippings, 1974, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
        - Notebooks, 1958, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
        - Notes, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6)
        - Print, undated (Box 28)
      - "The Poor Old Tunnel"--Galleys/Proofs, 1961, (3 folders) (Box 21)
      - "The Road Under the Silver Sea"--Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - "The Tunnel in the Chalk"--Galleys/Proofs, 1961 (Box 21)
      - The Tunnel under the Channel (book)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1962 (Box 28)
        - Simon and Schuster--Royalty Statement, 1963 (Box 6)
      - "The Tunnel under the Moat"
        - Galleys/Proofs, undated (Box 28)
        - Typescript, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Cigarettes
      - "A Cloud of Smoke"
        - American Tobacco Company--Press Releases, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1963 (Box 21)
        - Research Files
          - 1960-1964, 1960-1964 (Box 6)
          - Clippings, 1959-1963 (Box 6)
        - Tobacco Industry Research Committee--Press Releases, 1954-1963 (Box 6)
        - Typescript, 1963 (Box 6)
      - Comment (on Kent Cigarettes)--Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
      - Comment (on Real Cigarettes)--Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6)
      - "Cutting Down"
        - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1970 (Box 6)
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1970, (2 folders) (Box 22)
        - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - The Relaxed Sell
        - Book Reviews and Related Clippings, 1954, undated (Box 6)
        - Copyright Renewal, 1982 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence, 1953-1959 (Box 6)
        - Galleys/Proofs, undated (Box 28)
        - Oxford University Press, Inc.--Publicity Materials, 1954 (Box 6)
      - Research Files
        - Advertisements
          - 1963, undated (Box 6)
          - Television, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
        - Notebooks, 1969, undated, (5 folders) (Box 6)
        - Notes, 1969, undated, (6 folders) (Box 6)
        - Philip Morris History, undated (Box 6)
        - Tiderock Corporation, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
      - Selling Death: Cigarette Advertising and Public Health (book)
        - Book Reviews, 1972 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 6)
    - "Comment" (on chemical warfare)--Galleys/Proofs, 1981 (Box 7)
    - "Comment" (on the EPA)--Galleys/Proofs, 1979 (Box 7)
    - The Communicator
      - Correspondence, 1954 undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1954, (2 folders) (Box 22)
      - "Information Optimist"--Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - Research Files
        - 1951-1954, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7)
        - NBC Research Department, 1952-1953, (2 folders) (Box 7)
        - Notebooks, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
        - Notes
          - 1952-1954, undated, (12 folders) (Box 7)
          - Biographical Material, undated (Box 7)
          - Magazine Concept, undated (Box 7)
          - Public Service Projects, undated (Box 7)
          - "Today", 1952 (Box 7)
          - Wide Wide World, undated (Box 7)
        - Reel-to-Reel Audio, undated (2 reels) (Box 24)
        - Transcript, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Computer Crime
      - Computer Capers (book)
        - Book Reviews, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
        - Contract and Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
        - Correspondence (inc. John Kenneth Galbraith), 1976-1980, (3 folders) (Box 7)
      - "Dead Souls in the Computer"--Typescript, 1976, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
      - Interview Transcripts--Mansfield, Robert, 1969, 1975 (Box 8)
      - Research Files
        - 1971-1972, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 8)
        - Audits, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
        - Criminal Law, undated (Box 8)
        - Draper, John ("Captain Crunch"), 1976 (Box 8)
        - Notebooks, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
        - Notes, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
        - Penetration of Government Computer Systems, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - "Contaminated"
      - Correspondence, 1978-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8)
      - Draft, undated (Box 8)
      - Galley Inserts, undated (Box 8)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1978, (4 folders) (Box 8)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8)
      - Research Files, 1976 (Box 8)
      - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
      - Untitled--Galley/Proof, 1978 (Box 20)
      - "We're All Right"--Galleys/Proofs, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - "Corridor of Mirrors"
      - CBS
        - Correspondence Assignments, 1968 (Box 20)
        - Coverage Timeline, 1968, (4 folders) (Box 20)
        - Memoranda, 1968 (Box 20)
        - Press Releases, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 20)
        - Television Coverage--Transcript, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Columbia Journalism Review version, 1968 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Democratic National Convention Handbook, 1968 (Box 20)
      - Drafts, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Drafts (partial), undated (Box 20)
      - NBC--"Today's Inside Stories", 1968 (Box 9)
      - Nominating Speeches, 1968 (Box 9)
      - Public Addresses and Program, 1968 (Box 9)
      - Republican National Convention
        - Access Pass, 1968 (Box 9)
        - Handbook, 1968 (Box 9)
      - Research Files
        - 1966, 1968, undated, (8 folders) (Box 9)
        - Audiocassettes, undated (7 tapes) (Box 24a)
        - CBS Reports on Violence, 1968 (Box 9)
        - Nixon's Arrival, 1968 (Box 9)
        - Notebooks, undated, (5 folders) (Box 9)
        - Notes, undated (Box 9)
      - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - "A Countervailing Force"
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 9)
      - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - "The Couple Who Wouldn't Die"
      - Research Files
        - 1963 (Box 9)
        - Notebooks, undated (Box 9)
        - Notes, undated (Box 9)
        - Photographs and Negatives, undated (Box 9)
    - Emile Coue
      - "The Coue Method"--Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - "The Method of Emile Coue"--Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - "Culture by Punch Card"--Typescript, undated (Box 9)
    - "Dashin' About"
      - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (inc. Andy Rooney) (Box 10)
      - Draft, undated (Box 10)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1973 (Box 10)
      - Research Files
        - 1973, undated (Box 10)
        - Audiocassettes, undated (5 tapes) (Box 24a)
        - Audiocassettes, undated (10 tapes) (Box 24b)
        - Audiocassettes, undated (2 tapes) (Box 24e)
        - Notebooks, 1973, (4 folders) (Box 10)
        - Notes, 1973 undated, (3 folders) (Box 10)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 10)
      - Typescript/Draft, undated (Box 10)
    - "David Sandoff's Fabulous Fifty Years"--Galley, 1956 (Box 10)
    - Defoliation
      - Defoliation (book)
        - Book Reviews, 1970 (Box 10)
        - Publicity Materials, 1970, undated (Box 10)
      - "Defoliation"
        - Galleys/Proofs, 1970 (Box 22)
        - Reprint, 1970 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1976, (7 folders) (Box 10)
      - Research Files
        - 1967-1971, undated, (10 folders) (Box 10)
        - 2, 4, 5-T Advisory Committee Report, 1971 (Box 10)
        - Chloracne, 1961 1968-1970 (Box 11)
        - CS Gas/Meselson, Matthew, 1969 (Box 11)
        - Dioxins, FDA Studies on, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
        - Dow Chemical Company, 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
        - Herbicides, 1970, undated (Box 11)
        - Herbicides/Hanoi, undated (Box 11)
        - Hexachlorophene, 1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
        - Meselson, Matthew, 1971 (Box 11)
        - Notebooks, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11)
        - Notes, 1969 undated, (5 folders) (Box 11)
    - "Department of Amplification"
      - Galleys, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 11)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 22)
      - Research Files, 1970, undated (Box 11)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 11)
      - Galleys, 1971 (Box 11)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1971 (Box 22)
      - Galleys, 1981 (Box 11)
      - Typescript, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Typescript, 1979 (Box 11)
    - "Détente--ABC Style"
      - Correspondence
        - 1975 (Box 11)
        - AM America, 1975 (Box 11)
      - Galleys, undated (Box 11)
      - Research Files--Notes, undated (Box 11)
      - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - "Din-Din"
      - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 11)
      - Draft, undated (Box 11)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1976 (Box 11)
      - Typescript (partial), undated (Box 11)
    - "Down Past Joy"
      - Research Files
        - 1967-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 11)
        - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders
          - 1967, (2 folders) (Box 11)
          - Photographs, 1967 (Box 11)
        - Notebooks, undated, (6 folders) (Box 11)
        - Notes, 1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Typescript, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - "Getting There First with Tranquility"
      - Research Files
        - 1948-1958, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
        - Notes, 1957-1958, undated, (4 folders) (Box 12)
    - "Holy Smokestacks, What a Mess!"
      - Draft (partial), undated (Box 12)
      - Galleys/Proofs, 1956, undated (Box 22)
      - Research Files
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 12)
        - Notes, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
      - Typescript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - Typescript/Draft, undated (Box 12)
    - The Investigation of Ralph Nader: General Motors vs. One Determined Man (book)
      - Book Reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
      - Correspondence
        - 1971-1972 (Box 12)
        - Robert Lantz-Candida Donadio Literary Agents Incorporated, 1968-1972 (Box 12)
      - Publicity Materials, 1972 (Box 12)
      - Research Files
        - Articles by Nader, undated (Box 12)